<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Nebula Builders</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Nebula Builders</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yourdomain.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Architectural Digest Episode I: Apache Kafka ❤</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/apache-kafka/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yourdomain.com/posts/apache-kafka/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-kafka">Why Kafka?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Apache Kafka has always been one of my favourite technologies up to date. So I&amp;rsquo;m biased towards promoting it. That being said, the technology is a piece of art that can be used for everything under the sun from simple broker usage to large scale streaming solutions. Apache Kafka stands as a monumental innovation, offering unparalleled solutions to the challenges of data processing and streaming at scale. It was developed by Jay Kreps, Neha Narkhede, and Jun Rao at LinkedIn in 2010 and transcended its initial use case to become an elite platform for real-time data streaming, processing, and more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kubernetes 101: Intro to the Best Orchestrator in the World</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/kubernetes-101/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yourdomain.com/posts/kubernetes-101/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes solves several critical problems in modern software development, particularly in managing containerized applications. As applications grow in complexity, managing these containers manually becomes untenable. Kubernetes offers a solution by providing automated orchestration, ensuring applications run efficiently and reliably across clusters of servers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-brief-history-lesson">A Brief History Lesson&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Kubernetes, often abbreviated as K8s, has its roots in Google. Google&amp;rsquo;s extensive experience in running large-scale containerized applications led to the development of an internal project called Borg. Borg was designed to manage the thousands of containers running in Google&amp;rsquo;s vast data centers. Over time, Google recognized the potential benefits of open-sourcing a similar system to the broader community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Imaginary Cloud Empire: Unleashing Bare Metal Power with Kubernetes</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/imaginary-cloud-empire/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yourdomain.com/posts/imaginary-cloud-empire/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vision-redefining-cloud-computing-with-bare-metal-performance-and-cloud-flexibility">Vision: Redefining Cloud Computing with Bare Metal Performance and Cloud Flexibility&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the rapidly advancing world of cloud computing, the limitations of traditional virtualized environments are becoming increasingly evident. Our vision is to disrupt this space by merging the raw, untapped power of bare metal servers with the dynamic scalability of Kubernetes. This combination promises not just incremental improvements, but a radical leap in performance, efficiency, and flexibility - creating a platform that caters to the next generation of applications and services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing Disposable Software: Hexagonal Architecture and DDD for Flexible Codebase</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/disposable-software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yourdomain.com/posts/disposable-software/</guid><description>&lt;p>The article delves into the concept of &amp;ldquo;disposable software&amp;rdquo; — not in the sense of throwaway code, but rather in creating systems that are so flexible and well-structured that any part can be easily replaced or updated without disrupting the whole. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore how combining Hexagonal Architecture with Domain-Driven Design (DDD) principles, particularly in the Go programming language, can lead to more maintainable and adaptable codebases.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-disposable-mindset-a-first-principles-approach">The Disposable Mindset: A First Principles Approach&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To truly understand the concept of disposable software, let&amp;rsquo;s start with first principles. What are the fundamental truths about software development that we can build upon?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Architecting a State-of-the-Art Multi-Tenant Microservices Ecosystem for Accelerated Startup Development</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/my-startup-micros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yourdomain.com/posts/my-startup-micros/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the dynamic world of startups, the ability to rapidly ideate, prototype, and launch new products is paramount. This article presents a cutting-edge architecture for a reusable, multi-tenant microservices ecosystem designed to dramatically accelerate startup development. By leveraging advanced technologies, Domain-Driven Design principles, and focusing on crucial components such as authentication, subscription management, and user administration, this architecture provides a future-proof foundation for diverse SaaS applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="architectural-overview">Architectural Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The proposed ecosystem consists of highly specialized microservices, each meticulously designed to handle specific aspects of a modern SaaS application. These services operate in harmony, communicating through a sophisticated event-driven architecture to provide unparalleled flexibility and scalability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Custom Cluster Metrics Autoscaling in Amazon EKS</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/kubernetes-metrics-autoscaling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yourdomain.com/posts/kubernetes-metrics-autoscaling/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mastering-custom-cluster-metrics-autoscaling-in-amazon-eks-a-comprehensive-guide">Mastering Custom Cluster Metrics Autoscaling in Amazon EKS: A Comprehensive Guide&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In the ever-evolving landscape of cloud-native applications, the ability to efficiently manage resources is not just a luxury—it&amp;rsquo;s a necessity. As senior engineers, we&amp;rsquo;re often tasked with optimizing complex systems to ensure they&amp;rsquo;re both performant and cost-effective. Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) provides a robust platform for running containerized workloads, but its true power lies in how we leverage its features to create responsive, scalable systems. In this comprehensive guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive deep into implementing custom metrics autoscaling in Amazon EKS, equipping you with the knowledge to architect solutions that dynamically adapt to varying workloads.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comprehensive Social Media Platform Architecture: Microservices, Data Flow, and Infrastructure (Version 1)</title><link>https://yourdomain.com/posts/social-media-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yourdomain.com/posts/social-media-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the rapidly evolving landscape of social media platforms, building a scalable, resilient, and performant architecture is paramount. This article presents an in-depth overview of a modern social media platform architecture, focusing on how microservices interact, how data flows through the system, and how the underlying infrastructure supports millions of users while maintaining responsiveness, data integrity, and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the rationale behind our technical decisions, diving deep into the interplay between different components and how they contribute to a robust, scalable system. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the high-level infrastructure that supports this architecture, providing insights into how the system operates at scale.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>